 export const filme = [
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "In%20the%20movie%20%E2%80%9CThe%20Iron%20Giant%2C%E2%80%9D%20this%20character%20is%20the%20protagonist.",
"correct_answer": "Hogarth%20Hughes",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Kent%20Mansley",
"Dean%20McCoppin",
"Annie%20Hughes"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20retired%20American%20football%20quarterback%20played%20himself%20in%20%27Ace%20Ventura%3A%20Pet%20Detective%27%20and%20%27Little%20Nicky%27%3F",
"correct_answer": "Dan%20Marino",
"incorrect_answers": [
"John%20Elway",
"Tom%20Brady",
"Joe%20Montana"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "In%20which%201955%20film%20does%20Frank%20Sinatra%20play%20Nathan%20Detroit%3F",
"correct_answer": "Guys%20and%20Dolls",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Anchors%20Aweigh",
"From%20Here%20to%20Eternity",
"High%20Society"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Who%20directed%20the%201973%20film%20%22American%20Graffiti%22%3F",
"correct_answer": "George%20Lucas",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Ron%20Howard",
"Francis%20Ford%20Coppola",
"Steven%20Spielberg"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Who%20played%20Batman%20in%20the%201997%20film%20%22Batman%20and%20Robin%22%3F",
"correct_answer": "George%20Clooney",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Michael%20Keaton",
"Val%20Kilmer",
"Christian%20Bale"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "This%20movie%20contains%20the%20quote%2C%20%22I%20love%20the%20smell%20of%20napalm%20in%20the%20morning%21%22",
"correct_answer": "Apocalypse%20Now",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Platoon",
"The%20Deer%20Hunter",
"Full%20Metal%20Jacket"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "What%20is%20the%20name%20of%20the%20dog%20that%20played%20Toto%20in%20the%201939%20film%20%22The%20Wizard%20of%20Oz%22%3F",
"correct_answer": "Terry",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Tommy",
"Teddy",
"Toto"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "What%20does%20TIE%20stand%20for%20in%20reference%20to%20the%20TIE%20Fighter%20in%20%22Star%20Wars%22%3F",
"correct_answer": "Twin%20Ion%20Engine",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Twin%20Iron%20Engine",
"Twin%20Intercepter%20Engine",
"Twin%20Inception%20Engine"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "In%20the%201971%20film%20%22Willy%20Wonka%20%26%20the%20Chocolate%20Factory%22%2C%20who%20played%20Willy%20Wonka%3F",
"correct_answer": "Gene%20Wilder",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Shia%20LeBouf",
"Peter%20Ostrum",
"Johnny%20Depp"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Who%20plays%20the%20Nemesis%20in%20the%20Resident%20Evil%20movies%3F",
"correct_answer": "Matthew%20Taylor",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Jason%20Dip",
"Eric%20Mabius",
"Jimmy%20Matts"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "What%20is%20the%20name%20of%20the%20villian%20in%20the%202015%20Russian-American%20Sci-Fi%20Movie%20%22Hardcore%20Henry%22%3F",
"correct_answer": "Akan",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Estelle",
"Jimmy",
"Henry"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "In%20the%201979%20British%20film%20%22Quadrophenia%22%20what%20is%20the%20name%20of%20the%20main%20protagonist%3F",
"correct_answer": "Jimmy%20Cooper",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Pete%20Townshend",
"Franc%20Roddam",
"Archie%20Bunker"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20one%20of%20these%20actors%20is%20said%20to%20be%20cut%20from%20the%20film%20%27E.T.%20the%20Extra-Terrestrial%27%3F",
"correct_answer": "Harrison%20Ford",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Michael%20J.%20Fox",
"Andy%20Kaufman",
"Arnold%20Schwarzenegger"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20movie%20of%20film%20director%20Stanley%20Kubrick%20is%20known%20to%20be%20an%20adaptation%20of%20a%20Stephen%20King%20novel%3F",
"correct_answer": "The%20Shining",
"incorrect_answers": [
"2001%3A%20A%20Space%20Odyssey",
"%20Dr.%20Strangelove%20",
"Eyes%20Wide%20Shut"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "What%20was%20another%20suggested%20name%20for%2C%20the%201985%20film%2C%20Back%20to%20the%20Future%3F",
"correct_answer": "Spaceman%20From%20Pluto",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Hill%20Valley%20Time%20Travelers",
"The%20Time%20Travelers",
"The%20Lucky%20Man"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "What%20is%20the%20correct%20phrase%20for%20the%20Latin%20saying%20%22Romanes%20Eunt%20Domus%22%20in%20Monty%20Python%27s%20Life%20of%20Brian%3F",
"correct_answer": "Romani%20Ite%20Domum",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Romans%20Go%20Home",
"Roxani%20Ite%20Domum",
"Tomate%20Ite%20Domum"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Who%20played%20Sgt.%20Gordon%20Elias%20in%20%27Platoon%27%20%281986%29%3F",
"correct_answer": "Willem%20Dafoe",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Charlie%20Sheen",
"Matt%20Damon",
"Johnny%20Depp"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "In%20what%20year%20was%20the%20movie%20%22Police%20Academy%22%20released%3F",
"correct_answer": "1984",
"incorrect_answers": [
"1986",
"1985",
"1983"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "In%20The%20Lord%20of%20the%20Rings%3A%20The%20Fellowship%20of%20the%20Ring%2C%20which%20one%20of%20the%20following%20characters%20from%20the%20book%20was%20left%20out%20of%20the%20film%3F",
"correct_answer": "Tom%20Bombadil",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Strider",
"Barliman%20Butterbur",
"Celeborn"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "In%20the%201999%20movie%20Fight%20Club%2C%20which%20of%20these%20is%20not%20a%20rule%20of%20the%20%22fight%20club%22%3F",
"correct_answer": "Always%20wear%20a%20shirt",
"incorrect_answers": [
"You%20do%20not%20talk%20about%20FIGHT%20CLUB",
"Only%20two%20guys%20to%20a%20fight",
"Fights%20will%20go%20on%20as%20long%20as%20they%20have%20to"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20animated%20film%20did%20Steven%20Lisberger%20direct%20in%201980%20before%20going%20on%20to%20direct%20Tron%3F",
"correct_answer": "Animalympics",
"incorrect_answers": [
"The%20Fox%20and%20the%20Hound",
"The%20Black%20Cauldron",
"The%20Great%20Mouse%20Detecive"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "What%20year%20did%20the%20James%20Cameron%20film%20%22Titanic%22%20come%20out%20in%20theaters%3F",
"correct_answer": "1997",
"incorrect_answers": [
"1996",
"1998",
"1999"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Who%20voiced%20Metalbeard%20in%20%22The%20Lego%20Movie%22%3F",
"correct_answer": "Nick%20Offerman",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Liam%20Neeson",
"Morgan%20Freeman",
"Will%20Arnet"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "What%20was%20the%20name%20of%20the%20protagonist%20in%20the%20movie%20Commando%20%281985%29%3F",
"correct_answer": "John%20Matrix",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Ben%20Richards",
"Douglas%20Quaid",
"Harry%20Tasker"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Leonardo%20Di%20Caprio%20won%20his%20first%20Best%20Actor%20Oscar%20for%20his%20performance%20in%20which%20film%3F",
"correct_answer": "The%20Revenant",
"incorrect_answers": [
"The%20Wolf%20Of%20Wall%20Street",
"Shutter%20Island",
"Inception"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20documentary%20film%20maker%20wrote%20and%20starred%20in%20the%20film%20%22My%20Scientology%20Movie%22%20which%20first%20debuted%20in%202015%3F",
"correct_answer": "Louis%20Theroux",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Errol%20Morris",
"Joe%20Berlinger",
"Adam%20Curtis"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "In%20the%20%22Jurassic%20Park%22%20universe%2C%20what%20is%20the%20name%20of%20the%20island%20that%20contains%20InGen%27s%20Site%20B%3F",
"correct_answer": "Isla%20Sorna",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Isla%20Nublar",
"Isla%20Pena",
"Isla%20Muerta"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "What%20is%20the%20make%20and%20model%20of%20the%20tour%20vehicles%20in%20%22Jurassic%20Park%22%20%281993%29%3F",
"correct_answer": "1992%20Ford%20Explorer%20XLT",
"incorrect_answers": [
"1992%20Toyota%20Land%20Cruiser",
"1992%20Jeep%20Wrangler%20YJ%20Sahar",
"Mercedes%20M-Class"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "In%20%22Jurassic%20World%22%2C%20which%20company%20purchases%20InGen%20and%20creates%20Jurassic%20World%3F",
"correct_answer": "Masrani%20Global%20Corporation%20",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Biology%20Synthetics%20Technologies",
"International%20Genetics%20Incorporated",
"International%20Genetic%20Technologies"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Who%20plays%20%22Bruce%20Wayne%22%20in%20the%202008%20movie%20%22The%20Dark%20Knight%22%3F",
"correct_answer": "Christian%20Bale",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Michael%20Caine",
"Ron%20Dean",
"Heath%20Ledger"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20actor%20plays%20the%20character%20%22Tommy%20Jarvis%22%20in%20%22Friday%20the%2013th%3A%20The%20Final%20Chapter%22%20%281984%29%3F",
"correct_answer": "Corey%20Feldman",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Macaulay%20Culkin",
"Mel%20Gibson",
"Mark%20Hamill"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20former%20Star%20Trek%20actor%20directed%20Three%20Men%20and%20a%20Baby%20%281987%29%3F",
"correct_answer": "Leonard%20Nimoy",
"incorrect_answers": [
"William%20Shatner",
"George%20Takei",
"James%20Doohan"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20town%20is%20the%20setting%20for%20the%20Disney%20movie%20The%20Love%20Bug%20%281968%29%3F",
"correct_answer": "San%20Francisco",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Los%20Angeles",
"Sacramento",
"San%20Jose"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "What%20is%20Lilo%27s%20last%20name%20from%20Lilo%20and%20Stitch%3F",
"correct_answer": "Pelekai",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Anoa%CA%BBi",
"Kealoha",
"Ku%CA%BBulei"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "What%20is%20the%20name%20of%20the%20queen%27s%20pet%20in%20A%20Bug%27s%20Life%3F",
"correct_answer": "Aphie",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Flik",
"Hopper",
"Dot"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "In%20Finding%20Nemo%2C%20what%20was%20the%20name%20of%20Nemo%27s%20mom%3F",
"correct_answer": "Coral",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Sandy",
"Pearl",
"Shelly"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "In%20the%20Friday%20The%2013th%20series%2C%20what%20is%20Jason%27s%20mother%27s%20first%20name%3F",
"correct_answer": "Pamela",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Mary",
"Christine",
"Angeline"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20director%20directed%20the%20movie%20%22Pan%27s%20Labyrinth%22%3F",
"correct_answer": "Guillermo%20Del%20Toro",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Alfonso%20Cuar%C3%B3n",
"Alejandro%20Gonz%C3%A1lez%20I%C3%B1%C3%A1rritu",
"%20Alejandro%20Jodorowsky"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20stand-up%20comedian%20voiced%20the%20talking%20parrot%20%22Iago%22%20in%20Disney%27s%201992%20adaptation%20of%20Aladdin%3F",
"correct_answer": "Gilbert%20Gottfried",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Robin%20Williams",
"Pauly%20Shore",
"Jonathan%20Freeman"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20actor%20and%20martial%20artist%20starred%20as%20Colonel%20Guile%20in%20the%201994%20action%20film%20adaptation%20of%20Street%20Fighter%3F",
"correct_answer": "Jean-Claude%20Van%20Damme",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Chuck%20Norris",
"Steven%20Seagal",
"Scott%20Adkins"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Ed%20Koch%2C%20the%20Mayor%20of%20New%20York%20in%201984%2C%20played%20himself%20in%20which%20Muppets%20movie%3F",
"correct_answer": "The%20Muppets%20Take%20Manhattan",
"incorrect_answers": [
"The%20Great%20Muppet%20Caper",
"The%20Muppet%20Christmas%20Carol",
"The%20Muppet%20Movie"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20star%20actor%20was%20in%20%22Top%20Gun%22%2C%20%22Jerry%20Maguire%22%20and%20%22Born%20on%20the%20Fourth%20of%20July%22%3F",
"correct_answer": "Tom%20Cruise",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Kelly%20McGillis",
"John%20Travolta",
"George%20Clooney"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Brendan%20Fraser%20starred%20in%20the%20following%20movies%2C%20except%20which%20one%3F",
"correct_answer": "Titanic",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Monkeybone",
"Encino%20Man",
"Mrs.%20Winterbourne"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "In%20the%202014%20film%20%22Birdman%22%2C%20what%20is%20the%20primary%20instrument%20in%20the%20score%3F",
"correct_answer": "Drums",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Saxophone",
"Violin",
"Actual%20Live%20Birds%20Singing"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20Marvel%20superhero%20did%20Chris%20Evans%20play%20prior%20to%20his%20role%20as%20Captain%20America%3F",
"correct_answer": "Human%20Torch",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Cyclops",
"Iceman",
"Daredevil"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "Which%20of%20the%20following%20films%20was%20NOT%20directed%20by%20Quentin%20Tarantino%3F",
"correct_answer": "From%20Dusk%20till%20Dawn",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Jackie%20Brown",
"Pulp%20Fiction",
"Reservoir%20Dogs"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "In%20the%20film%20%22Requiem%20for%20a%20Dream%22%2C%20what%20drug%20does%20Jared%20Leto%27s%20character%20get%20addicted%20to%3F",
"correct_answer": "Heroin",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Cocaine",
"Marijuana",
"Oxycodone"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "What%20is%20the%20name%20of%20the%20character%20Nicolas%20Cage%20plays%20in%20the%20movie%20%22National%20Treasure%3F%22",
"correct_answer": "Benjamin%20Franklin%20Gates",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Thomas%20Jefferson%20Walker",
"George%20Washington%20Swanson",
"John%20Quincy%20Beckett"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "What%20is%20the%20name%20of%20the%20foley%20artist%20who%20designed%20the%20famous%20sounds%20of%20Star%20Wars%2C%20including%20Chewbacca%27s%20roar%20and%20R2-D2%27s%20beeps%20and%20whistles%3F",
"correct_answer": "Ben%20Burtt",
"incorrect_answers": [
"Ken%20Burns",
"Ralph%20McQuarrie",
"Miranda%20Keyes"
]
},
{
"category": "Entertainment%3A%20Film",
"type": "multiple",
"difficulty": "medium",
"question": "About%20how%20much%20money%20did%20it%20cost%20for%20Tommy%20Wiseau%20to%20make%20his%20masterpiece%20%22The%20Room%22%20%282003%29%3F",
"correct_answer": "%246%20Million",
"incorrect_answers": [
"%2420%2C000",
"%241%20Million",
"%2410%20Million"
]
}
]
